# Richard R Garcia

San Antonio, TX | (210) 726-3510 | drkslate@outlook.es | LinkedIn

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

A professional with experience in IT and warehousing, quality assurance, time management and customer service. Strong soft and hard skills and proficient in Spanish and English communication. A motivated partner to learn and apply all the knowledge gathered through experience even on under pressure moments.

#### **EDUCATION**

UniversityDegree, MajorDate Degree ReceivedPolytechnic University of San Luis PotosíBachelor of Science in information technologyApr, 2024

#### **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

Soft Skills: Colaboration, Interpersonal, Adaptability, Organization, Intrapersonal.

Hard Skills: Power BI, Excel, Data Analysis, SQL, Python. Competences: Networking, Communication, Logic, Coding.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

HEB, Distribution Partner II, San Antonio, Tx

Jun 2024 - Present

- Work with high accuracy to complete assignments in time and order according the OSTP and HEB Way.
- Collaborate with partners in Spanish and English teamwork to accomplish objectives.
- Exceeded expectations pulling over the 85% required per day on assignments.
- Work with machinery as barrets and good control of work under pressure.

Grupo ABG, IT Intern, San Luis Potosí, SLP, México

Jul 2023 - Jan 2024

- Worked on software development using agile methodologies.
- Completed the goals and objectives according to the Grupo ABG Vision.
- Worked on technical support for the different customers across nationwide.
- Collaborate with different teams to complement the development of staff reports.

Cummins Inc., Business Intelligence Analyst Intern, San Luis Potosi, SLP, Mexico

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

- Worked on automation of common processes for improve time management.
- Collaborate with different teams across worldwide to complement the development of staff reports.
- Worked on databases and data modeling to develop tools for staff.
- Complete the expectations on the tools development through BI tools usage.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

## **MICROSOFT OFFICE SPECIALIST CERTIFICATION (MOS)**

Microsoft, Microsoft | Dec 2017 Credential ID 90016247

## ANALYZING AND VISUALIZING DATA WITH MICROSOFT POWER BI

Microsoft, San Luis Potosí | Sep. 2022 Credential ID 90016247

# **SCRUM FOUND PROFESIONAL CERTIFICATE**

CertiProf International, San Luis Potosí | May 2023

Credential ID 85871434